[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "The Philosophy of co-operation looks upon it as a means of redistribution of income and wealth by eliminating conflict",
    "options": ["Evolutionary", "Revolutionary", "Economic", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Economic"
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "In India before independence co-operative movement was",
    "options": ["Under the influence of social workers", "Under the control of agriculturists", "Under full political control", "Above the care of political leaders"],
    "answer": "Under the influence of social workers"
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "Which one of the following is not one of the economic benefits of co-operation?",
    "options": ["It ends exploitation", "No equitable distribution of profit", "Monopolitic trends are challenged", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "No equitable distribution of profit"
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "Abat system of Co-operation prevails among",
    "options": ["The tribals", "Rajputs", "The big zamindars", "All the above"],
    "answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "The first Co-operative Societies Act was passed in India in the year",
    "options": ["1904", "1912", "1909", "1906"],
    "answer": "1904"
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "Which one of the following is the point of similarity between Raiffesion Banks and Delitizch Banks?",
    "options": ["In both cases there are indivisible reserve fund", "In both cases shares are highly priced", "In both cases whole management is run democratically", "In both cases interests of borrowers have major consideration"],
    "answer": "In both cases whole management is run democratically"
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "Land development Banks provide loans on",
    "options": ["Short term basis", "Medium term basis", "Long term basis", "All the above"],
    "answer": "Long term basis"
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "The year in which Non-credit Co-operative societies were started in India",
    "options": ["1912", "1918", "1914", "1916"],
    "answer": "1912"
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "Under co-operative audit, a system of audit of which is made a continuous process is called",
    "options": ["Concurrent audit", "Balance sheet audit", "Interim audit", "Test audit"],
    "answer": "Concurrent audit"
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "Who organise the first co-operative society of shoe makers in Germany?",
    "options": ["Hermann", "Raiffeissen", "Delitizch", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "Delitizch"
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following co-operative societies has great success in Denmark?",
    "options": ["Marketing", "Dairying", "Industrial", "Eggs"],
    "answer": "Dairying"
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "The type of society which arranges for farm needs of agriculturists is called",
    "options": ["Service societies", "Marketing societies", "Trading societies", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Service societies"
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "Which one of the following is not one of the characteristics of Raiffesein societies",
    "options": ["Very small amount of loans are advanced", "Share value should be very nominal", "Societies should be of large size", "Majority of members are farmers"],
    "answer": "Societies should be of large size"
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "In Japan Co-operative movement started in the year",
    "options": ["1878", "1880", "1881", "1879"],
    "answer": "1878"
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "Who was started the first Industrial Co-operative society of blacksmiths in China?",
    "options": ["Dr. Sunyatsen", "Chou-En-Lai", "Mao Tse Tung", "C.F. Wu"],
    "answer": "C.F. Wu"
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "Who inspire the starting of co-operative movement in Ireland?",
    "options": ["Roachdale Pioneers", "Hoarce Plunkett", "P.J. Tardy", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Hoarce Plunkett"
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "Which one of the following is an economic benefit of co-operative movement in India?",
    "options": ["It has developed democratic spirit", "It has increased social contacts of workers", "It has increased social prestige of workers", "It has saved the agriculturists from money-Lenders"],
    "answer": "It has saved the agriculturists from money-Lenders"
  },
  {
    "number": 18,
    "question": "Which one of the following is not an important function of state Co-operative Bank?",
    "options": ["To act as banker's Bank", "To organise trade fairs in cities", "To help in mobilising financial resources", "To create better relationship between Co-operative societies"],
    "answer": "To organise trade fairs in cities"
  },
  {
    "number": 19,
    "question": "The year in which Reserve Bank of India Act Passed?",
    "options": ["1949", "1935", "1934", "1950"],
    "answer": "1934"
  },
  {
    "number": 20,
    "question": "Royal commission on agriculture in India was set up in the year",
    "options": ["1927", "1929", "1926", "1928"],
    "answer": "1928"
  },
  {
    "number": 21,
    "question": "An agreement comes into existence by the process of offer by one party and its acceptance by the other party",
    "options": ["Qualified", "Effected", "Ineffective", "Unqualified"],
    "answer": "Unqualified"
  },
  {
    "number": 22,
    "question": "An act constituting consideration must have been done at the desire or request of the",
    "options": ["Promisee", "Any other person", "Promisor", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Promisor"
  },
  {
    "number": 23,
    "question": "When a person is compelled to enter into a contract by the use of force by the other party or under a threat is called",
    "options": ["Mistake", "Misrepresentation", "Undue influence", "Coercion"],
    "answer": "Coercion"
  },
  {
    "number": 24,
    "question": "A contract to do or not to do something if some event collateral to such contract does or does not happen is called",
    "options": ["Contingent contract", "Absolute contract", "In effected contract", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Contingent contract"
  },
  {
    "number": 25,
    "question": "Monetary compensation allowed to the injured party by the court for the loss or injury suffered by him by the breach of a contract is called",
    "options": ["Damage", "Damages", "Integrum", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Damages"
  },
  {
    "number": 26,
    "question": "A Contract by which one party promises to save from loss caused to him by the conduct of the promisor himself or by the conduct of any other person is",
    "options": ["Contract of indemnity", "Contract of guarantee", "Contract of uberrimae fidei", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Contract of indemnity"
  },
  {
    "number": 27,
    "question": "The right of a person to retain possession of some goods belonging to another until some debt or claim of the person in possession is satisfied is called",
    "options": ["Pledge", "Mortgage", "Hypothication", "Lien"],
    "answer": "Lien"
  },
  {
    "number": 28,
    "question": "Under a contract of sale, the transfer of the property in the goods is to take place at a future time is a",
    "options": ["Sale", "Agreement to sell", "Bailment", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Agreement to sell"
  },
  {
    "number": 29,
    "question": "The year in which the foreign exchange management Act was passed in India",
    "options": ["3rd December 1999", "5th December 1999", "10th December 1999", "2nd December 1999"],
    "answer": "3rd December 1999"
  },
  {
    "number": 30,
    "question": "A prospectus which does not have details of either price or number of shares being offered or the amount of issue is called",
    "options": ["Abridged prospectus", "Offer document", "Draft offer document", "Red Herring prospectus"],
    "answer": "Red Herring prospectus"
  },
  {
    "number": 31,
    "question": "If a company borrows money beyond its express or implied powers, the borrowing is the company and is void",
    "options": ["Ultra vires", "Intra vires", "Injunction", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Ultra vires"
  },
  {
    "number": 32,
    "question": "The year in which payment of Bonus Act was passed in India?",
    "options": ["1975", "1964", "1985", "1965"],
    "answer": "1965"
  },
  {
    "number": 33,
    "question": "Export import Bank of India was setup in 1982 as a wholly owned undertaking of the",
    "options": ["Private individual", "Foreigners", "Government of India", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Government of India"
  },
  {
    "number": 34,
    "question": "Balance sheet is a statement of the financial position of a concern",
    "options": ["For the year ended", "As on a particular date", "For a given period", "All the above"],
    "answer": "As on a particular date"
  },
  {
    "number": 35,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a profitability ratio?",
    "options": ["Earning per share", "Earning yield", "Dividend yield", "Operating profit ratio"],
    "answer": "Dividend yield"
  },
  {
    "number": 36,
    "question": "The term funds means in cash flow analysis",
    "options": ["Cash", "Total funds", "Total assets", "Fixed assets"],
    "answer": "Cash"
  },
  {
    "number": 37,
    "question": "When fixed costs is ₹20,000 and profit volume ratio is 25 percent, then break even point will be",
    "options": ["₹ 60,000", "10,000 unit", "80,000 unit", "₹ 80,000"],
    "answer": "₹ 80,000"
  },
  {
    "number": 38,
    "question": "Management Information system relates to",
    "options": ["External intelligence", "Internal intelligence", "Internal and External intelligence", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Internal and External intelligence"
  },
  {
    "number": 39,
    "question": "A and B are partners sharing the profit in the proportion of 7:3. They admit C by giving 1/6th share in the profit. The new profit sharing ratio of A, B and C is",
    "options": ["7:3:2", "7:2:3", "7:3:5", "7:3:4"],
    "answer": "7:3:2"
  },
  {
    "number": 40,
    "question": "Allotment of shares on pro-rata means",
    "options": ["Allotment on the basis of first come first serve", "Equal allotment on every application", "Allotment on every application in the ratio which the total numbers of shares to be allotted bears to total number of shares applied", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Allotment on every application in the ratio which the total numbers of shares to be allotted bears to total number of shares applied"
  },
  {
    "number": 41,
    "question": "Naked debentures are",
    "options": ["Unsecured", "Secured on floating", "Secured on fixed charge", "Both (A) and (B)"],
    "answer": "Unsecured"
  },
  {
    "number": 42,
    "question": "Bonus shares are issued to the equity shareholders",
    "options": ["At discount", "Without any consideration", "With consideration", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Without any consideration"
  },
  {
    "number": 43,
    "question": "Elton Mayo was the father of",
    "options": ["Scientific management", "Process management", "Human relation school", "Empirical school"],
    "answer": "Human relation school"
  },
  {
    "number": 44,
    "question": "The term permanent working capital and core current assets are",
    "options": ["Anonymous", "Different terms", "Synonymous", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Synonymous"
  },
  {
    "number": 45,
    "question": "The main object of providing depreciation on fixed asset",
    "options": ["For correct valuation of fixed asset", "For correct calculation of profit", "Creation of internal reserve for replacement of asset", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Creation of internal reserve for replacement of asset"
  },
  {
    "number": 46,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a cash inflow?",
    "options": ["Cash received from debtors", "Sale of fixed asset", "Issue of debentures", "Cash from business operations"],
    "answer": "Issue of debentures"
  },
  {
    "number": 47,
    "question": "Table 'A' of Companies Act 1956 gives",
    "options": ["A model of day book", "A model of Trading Account", "A model of Resolution", "A model of Articles of association"],
    "answer": "A model of Articles of association"
  },
  {
    "number": 48,
    "question": "Under which one of the following methods of depreciation is the amount of the assets reduced to zero",
    "options": ["Diminishing balance method", "Straight line method", "Annuity method", "Digit line method"],
    "answer": "Straight line method"
  },
  {
    "number": 49,
    "question": "Right's shares are the shares that are offered to the",
    "options": ["Debenture holders", "Preference share holders", "Creditors of the company", "Existing equity shareholders"],
    "answer": "Existing equity shareholders"
  },
  {
    "number": 50,
    "question": "In the absence of any contract, capital profit arising on dissolution of a partnership firm is credited to the partner's capital account",
    "options": ["Profit sharing ratio", "Equal proportion", "Capital ratio", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Profit sharing ratio"
  },
  {
    "number": 51,
    "question": "Which of the stock broker expects the price of securities to decline in the near future?",
    "options": ["Bear", "Stag", "Lame duck", "Bull"],
    "answer": "Bear"
  },
  {
    "number": 52,
    "question": "Average clause in a fire policy is inserted in order to check mainly",
    "options": ["Over insurance", "Under insurance", "Both (A) and (B)", "All of the above"],
    "answer": "Over insurance"
  },
  {
    "number": 53,
    "question": "The gilt-edged market refers to the market for",
    "options": ["Public limited company securities", "Shares and debentures", "Government and Semi-Government securities", "Industrial Securities"],
    "answer": "Government and Semi-Government securities"
  },
  {
    "number": 54,
    "question": "Setting the mission which emphasizes objectives, policies and aims in an organisation is known as",
    "options": ["Strategic planning", "Contingency planning", "Tactical planning", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "Strategic planning"
  },
  {
    "number": 55,
    "question": "Proxy is appointed by a shareholder to",
    "options": ["To speak at a meeting of the debenture holders", "To attend the meeting without the right to vote or speak", "Vote at meeting of the shareholders", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Vote at meeting of the shareholders"
  },
  {
    "number": 56,
    "question": "Grapevine is",
    "options": ["Officially created relationship by management", "As a result of social contacts", "Injurious to management", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "As a result of social contacts"
  },
  {
    "number": 57,
    "question": "The chief advantage of committee organisation is",
    "options": ["Greater participation", "Divide responsibility", "Quick decision", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Greater participation"
  },
  {
    "number": 58,
    "question": "_____ discount is a price reduction given to the buyers who promptly pay their bills.",
    "options": ["Seasonal discount", "Quantity discount", "Functional discount", "Cash discount"],
    "answer": "Cash discount"
  },
  {
    "number": 59,
    "question": "Marginal revenue will be zero if the elasticity of demand is",
    "options": ["Equal to zero", "Less than one", "More than one", "Equal to one"],
    "answer": "Equal to one"
  },
  {
    "number": 60,
    "question": "Boom period is represented by",
    "options": ["Disguised unemployment", "Under employment", "Full employment", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Full employment"
  },
  {
    "number": 61,
    "question": "Which of the following acts as a medium of communication between the user and computer hardware?",
    "options": ["Application software", "Operating system", "Keyboard", "RAM"],
    "answer": "Operating system"
  },
  {
    "number": 62,
    "question": "Resident monitor, used in many early computers is a piece of",
    "options": ["Hardware", "Application software", "System Software", "None of these"],
    "answer": "System Software"
  },
  {
    "number": 63,
    "question": "Which uses vector based drawing methods?",
    "options": ["Paint program", "Adobe Photoshop", "Corel draw", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Corel draw"
  },
  {
    "number": 64,
    "question": "One Gigabyte is equivalent to",
    "options": ["1024 MB", "1 Kilo Byte", "512 MB", "None of these"],
    "answer": "1024 MB"
  },
  {
    "number": 65,
    "question": "EDI Stands for",
    "options": ["Electronic Data Interchange", "Electronic Data and Information", "Electronic Data Interface", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Electronic Data Interchange"
  },
  {
    "number": 66,
    "question": "In which mode communication is bi-directional?",
    "options": ["Half duplex", "Full duplex", "Both (A) and (B)", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Full duplex"
  },
  {
    "number": 67,
    "question": "Objects with the same structure and behavior belongs to a",
    "options": ["Structure", "Package", "Packet", "Class"],
    "answer": "Class"
  },
  {
    "number": 68,
    "question": "In software design which one is used for specifying functional requirements?",
    "options": ["Flow chart", "Flow graph", "Data flow diagrams", "Both (A) and (B)"],
    "answer": "Data flow diagrams"
  },
  {
    "number": 69,
    "question": "The possible cardinality ratio for binary relationship types is",
    "options": ["1:1", "1:N", "M:N", "All of these"],
    "answer": "All of these"
  },
  {
    "number": 70,
    "question": "The central part of Linux operating system is",
    "options": ["System utilities", "Kernel", "Shell", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Kernel"
  },
  {
    "number": 71,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a software quality model?",
    "options": ["Mc Call Model", "ISO 9000", "ISO 9126", "Boehm model"],
    "answer": "ISO 9000"
  },
  {
    "number": 72,
    "question": "In Excel, 'Editing' group is available in _____ tab.",
    "options": ["Home", "Data", "Insert", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Home"
  },
  {
    "number": 73,
    "question": "A structured display of information along with graphics sound etc is called",
    "options": ["Page", "Message", "Slide", "Presentation"],
    "answer": "Presentation"
  },
  {
    "number": 74,
    "question": "Which of the following gives the address of a Webpage?",
    "options": ["URL", "Unicode", "UDP", "None of these"],
    "answer": "URL"
  },
  {
    "number": 75,
    "question": "Which among the following is used to view a website?",
    "options": ["Search engine", "Web browser", "Hyperlink", "Resource locator"],
    "answer": "Web browser"
  },
  {
    "number": 76,
    "question": "Which is not a type of alignment in MS Word?",
    "options": ["Centre", "Justify", "Spacing", "None of these"],
    "answer": "Spacing"
  },
  {
    "number": 77,
    "question": "In MS Word shift and right arrow key is used to _____ the text.",
    "options": ["Delete", "Select", "Copy", "Cut"],
    "answer": "Select"
  },
  {
    "number": 78,
    "question": "MS PowerPoint files are saved with _____ extension.",
    "options": ["pwt", "prs", "pot", "ppt"],
    "answer": "ppt"
  },
  {
    "number": 79,
    "question": "Which memory is known as volatile?",
    "options": ["RAM", "ROM", "Both (A) and (B)", "None of these"],
    "answer": "RAM"
  },
  {
    "number": 80,
    "question": "Which of the following can be used as a connecting device between two separate networks using different communication protocols?",
    "options": ["Router", "Bridge", "Hub", "Gateway"],
    "answer": "Gateway"
  },
  {
    "number": 81,
    "question": "The first implantation of artificial heart was conducted on December 18, 2013 under the leadership of",
    "options": ["Dr. D.H. Frazier", "Dr. Alain F. Carpentier", "Dr. William Cohn", "Dr. Clifford Kwan Gett"],
    "answer": "Dr. Alain F. Carpentier"
  },
  {
    "number": 82,
    "question": "The recipient of Col. C.K. Nayudu Life time achievement award of the year 2013 is",
    "options": ["Sunil Gavaskar", "Ajit Wadekar", "Kapil Dev", "Gundappa Viswanath"],
    "answer": "Gundappa Viswanath"
  },
  {
    "number": 83,
    "question": "The winner of the Miss universe contest of the year 2013",
    "options": ["Ms. Patricia Yurena Rodriguez", "Ms. Gabriela Isler", "Ms. Constanza Baez", "Ms. Manasi Moghe"],
    "answer": "Ms. Gabriela Isler"
  },
  {
    "number": 84,
    "question": "The only union territory which has a high court of its own",
    "options": ["Lakshadweep", "Chandigarh", "Daman and Diu", "Delhi"],
    "answer": "Delhi"
  },
  {
    "number": 85,
    "question": "The social reformer who is known as 'Lincoln of Kerala'",
    "options": ["Chattampi Swamikal", "Pandit Karuppan", "Sree Narayana Guru", "Thycaud Ayya"],
    "answer": "Pandit Karuppan"
  },
  {
    "number": 86,
    "question": "'Prathyaksha Raksha Daiva Sabha' was founded by",
    "options": ["Kuriakose Elias Chavara", "Ayya Vaikundar", "Poikayil Yohannan", "Brahmananda Swami Sivayogi"],
    "answer": "Poikayil Yohannan"
  },
  {
    "number": 87,
    "question": "The university of Kerala came into existence in",
    "options": ["1952", "1968", "1957", "1984"],
    "answer": "1957"
  },
  {
    "number": 88,
    "question": "Who won the Wimbledon Tennis men's singles in 2013?",
    "options": ["Novak Djokovic", "Mike Bryan", "Rafael Nadal", "Andy Murray"],
    "answer": "Andy Murray"
  },
  {
    "number": 89,
    "question": "Who won the Asian Cup Hockey held at Malaysia in 2013?",
    "options": ["South Korea", "India", "Pakistan", "Netherlands"],
    "answer": "India"
  },
  {
    "number": 90,
    "question": "The viceroy who partitioned Bengal was",
    "options": ["Lord Rippon", "Lord Lytton", "Lord Canning", "Lord Curzon"],
    "answer": "Lord Curzon"
  },
  {
    "number": 91,
    "question": "The Abhinav Bharat society was organised by",
    "options": ["V.D. Savarkar", "Sukhdev", "Raj Guru", "Chandra Shekhar Azad"],
    "answer": "V.D. Savarkar"
  },
  {
    "number": 92,
    "question": "The Chauri-Chaura incident took place in connection with",
    "options": ["Civil disobedience movement", "Anti-partition movement", "Non-Cooperation movement", "Khilafath movement"],
    "answer": "Non-Cooperation movement"
  },
  {
    "number": 93,
    "question": "The Quit India resolution was passed after the failure of",
    "options": ["August offer", "Cripps Mission", "Nehru Report", "Simon Commission"],
    "answer": "Cripps Mission"
  },
  {
    "number": 94,
    "question": "The Azad Hind Fauj was formed in",
    "options": ["July 1943", "July 1946", "July 1940", "July 1939"],
    "answer": "July 1943"
  },
  {
    "number": 95,
    "question": "The first Mahila bank of the country named Bharatiya Mahila Bank was inaugurated in",
    "options": ["Chennai", "Mumbai", "Delhi", "Guwahati"],
    "answer": "Delhi"
  },
  {
    "number": 96,
    "question": "The present Chairman of ISRO is",
    "options": ["Dr. G. Madhavan Nair", "Dr. Krishnaswamy", "K. Radhakrishnan", "Dr. Kasthoorirangan"],
    "answer": "K. Radhakrishnan"
  },
  {
    "number": 97,
    "question": "'NAMMA METRO' is the metro rail system of",
    "options": ["Hyderabad", "Chennai", "Mumbai", "Bangalore"],
    "answer": "Bangalore"
  },
  {
    "number": 98,
    "question": "The Fertilisers and Chemicals Travancore Limited was started during the period of",
    "options": ["Srichithira Thirunal", "Swathi Thirunal", "Aayiliam Thirunal", "Sree Moolam Thirunal"],
    "answer": "Sree Moolam Thirunal"
  },
  {
    "number": 99,
    "question": "The Egyptian pilot Hippalus discovered the monsoon wind in",
    "options": ["40 AD", "50 AD", "54 AD", "45 AD"],
    "answer": "45 AD"
  },
  {
    "number": 100,
    "question": "The Sulaiman mountain ranges situates in which part of India?",
    "options": ["North west", "North", "North east", "East"],
    "answer": "North west"
  }
]